ausregistry.com.au 2015-04-18

# AusRegistry - .au Registry Provider - Privacy Policy

##   Privacy Policy

Introduction

AusRegistry Pty. Ltd. (ACN 092 242 209) ( **AusRegistry, we** , **us** or **our** ) believe that privacy is an important individual right and is important to our own business and to our clients.  
We are committed to ensuring the privacy of individuals and we will endeavour to abide by the Australian Privacy Principles, as set out in the _Privacy Act_ (Cth) 1988.  
This Policy sets out how we collect, use and manage personal information that we receive about individuals, and deals with the following:

  * the _Privacy Act_ 1988;
  * the kinds of personal information that we collect and hold;
  * how and for what purposes we collect and hold personal information
  * the purposes for which we collect, hold, use and disclose personal information
  * protection of personal information;
  * your rights of access to and correction of personal information we hold about you;
  * making a complaint about a breach by us of the Australian Privacy Principles, and how we will deal with such;
  * if we are likely to disclose personal information to overseas recipients, and if so where; and
  * how to contact us.

These are set out below.

The _Privacy Act 1988_ (the **Act** ), regulates the way in which many private sector organisations in Australia collect, use, store and disclose personal information.   
Personal information is defined under the Act as:

_“...information or an opinion about an identified individual, or an individual who is reasonably identifiable, whether the information or opinion is true or not and whether the information or opinion is recorded in a material form or not.”_

The Act aims to give people greater control over the way information about them is handled, by requiring organisations to comply with thirteen Australian Privacy Principles or to establish an approved privacy code.

The Australian Privacy Principles cover areas such as collection, use and disclosure of personal information, data quality and security and access and correction rights for individuals.

**How we collect personal information** We generally collect personal information directly from the relevant individual but in some cases we may collect it indirectly from a third party, for example from domain name Registrars to whom you have given registration information. There may be other circumstances in which we may collect personal information about an individual, such as the operation of our website www.

ausregistry.com.au.

**Information about individuals** Personal information collected by us generally comprises name, address, date of birth, gender and contact details (including telephone, facsimile and e-mail). Personal information is only accessible by authorised AusRegistry personnel or authorised service providers who use the information accurately to administer the business of AusRegistry or to provide you with our products and services.

**Why do we need your personal information** **?** The personal information that we collect is used by us to conduct our business and is also used in conjunction with the provision of goods and services to you by AusRegistry.  
Personal information may also be used in connection with:

  * administering our customer relationships;
  * monitoring and evaluating products and services;
  * assisting customers with queries;
  * taking measures to detect and prevent fraudulent conduct; and
  * performing and responding to obligations that we have to regulatory or governmental authorities, for example displaying WHOIS information.

_Third party service providers  
_There are other organisations that are connected to the services we provide to you and which may have access to your personal information. They include:

  * Auditors and Legal Advisers – organisations that ensure we are complying with legislation and contractual obligations.
  * Insurance companies – organisations which provide insurance cover for our assets.
  * IT service providers – organisations maintaining our information technology systems and providing information technology services.

We will only disclose personal information to these organisations to enable them to undertake specified management and administration services. We require our service providers to adhere to strict privacy guidelines and not to keep this information or use it for any unauthorised purposes.

_Transfer outside of Australia_ Our holding, use and disclosure of your personal information may involve transfer of the personal information to countries outside Australia. Where your personal information is transferred outside Australia, we will do so in accordance with Australian Privacy Principle 8, including taking reasonable steps to ensure that the overseas recipient does not breach the Australian Privacy Principles.

_Legal disclosure requirements_ We will also disclose personal information in circumstances where we are required by law to do so. This includes disclosure to certain courts, tribunals and regulatory authorities as authorised or required by law.

_Other people authorised by you_ Where a person authorises another party to receive information and/or undertake transactions, the authorising person must notify us in writing.

_Use of general statistical information_ From time to time we may use general statistical information for future planning so that we can improve our business. If you do not consent to us doing so, please let us know.

_Unsolicited Information_ Where we receive personal information about you that is unsolicited, if it is not reasonably necessary for one or more of the uses set out herein, we shall de-identify or destroy it as soon as practicable.

_Direct communication_ We may send relevant communication material to you from time to time, such as direct communications (which may include information from third parties) about special offers and promotions that are available for you, where you have given express or implied consent to be included in our mailing list. __If you do not want us to use your personal information to send you direct marketing material, or, if not disclosed by you, you would like to know the source of the personal information we hold, then please phone +61 3 98663710. In the case of e-mail communications, you may also use the “unsubscribe” facility contained in our e-mails. Once you have unsubscribed from our mailing list, we will refrain from contacting you unless we are directed to do so by any governmental or regulatory authority, in the case of an emergency situation or where we are otherwise required or permitted to do so by law.

**How we manage your personal information** **?** __We take reasonable steps to keep any personal information which we hold about you secure, to avoid interference, and to keep that information accurate and up to date. _  
_ Internally we have controls and procedures to ensure that personal information provided to us remains confidential. All our staff are bound by strict rules and duties of confidentiality. _  
_ Unfortunately, no data transmission over the internet can be guaranteed to be 100% secure. As a result, while we employ commercially reasonable security measures to protect data and seek to partner with companies which do the same, however, we cannot guarantee the security of any personal information transmitted to or from our website, and we are not responsible for the actions of any third party that may receive such personal information.

**Can you see the personal information we have about you?**

You have a right to know what information we hold about you, and you can contact us and ask us to show you this information to ensure it is correct. Please note that information that we hold about you may be subject to the requirements of various regulatory or governmental authorities. In that regard, we will comply with the requirements of those regulatory or governmental authorities in releasing any information to you.

We will take all steps reasonable in the circumstances to ensure that the personal information we hold about you is accurate, up to date and complete. However, if you would like to make any corrections to your personal information you can [contact us](mailto:%3Cscript%20type='text/javascript'%3E%20%3C!--%20var%20prefix%20=%20'ma'%20+%20'il'%20+%20'to';%20var%20path%20=%20'hr'%20+%20'ef'%20+%20'=';%20var%20addy42535%20=%20'info'%20+%20'@';%20addy42535%20=%20addy42535%20+%20'ausregistry'%20+%20'.'%20+%20'com'%20+%20'.'%20+%20'au';%20document.write\('%3Ca%20'%20+%20path%20+%20'\\''%20+%20prefix%20+%20':'%20+%20addy42535%20+%20'\\'%3E'\);%20document.write\(addy42535\);%20document.write\('%3C\\/a%3E'\);%20//--%3E\\n%20%3C/script%3E%3Cscript%20type='text/javascript'%3E%20%3C!--%20document.write\('%3Cspan%20style=\\'display:%20none;\\'%3E'\);%20//--%3E%20%3C/script%3EThis%20email%20address%20is%20being%20protected%20from%20spambots.%20You%20need%20JavaScript%20enabled%20to%20view%20it.%20%3Cscript%20type='text/javascript'%3E%20%3C!--%20document.write\('%3C/'\);%20document.write\('span%3E'\);%20//--%3E%20%3C/script%3E) in writing at the address designated in this document.

Under the Australian Privacy Principles there are limited circumstances in which access to some or all of this information may be denied. If this applies to you, we will explain this to you when you ask for your information. Otherwise we will endeavour to provide you with your information within a period of 30 days, depending on the amount of information required.

**Cookies**

At times, we may utilise “cookies” which enable us to monitor traffic patterns and to serve you more efficiently if you revisit the site. A cookie does not identify you personally but it does identify your computer. You can set your browser to notify you when you receive a cookie and this will provide you with an opportunity to either accept or reject it in each instance.

**Hyperlinks to other web sites**

This website may contain hyperlinks to web sites owned and operated by third parties. These third party web sites have their own privacy policies and we urge you to review them. They will govern the use of personal information you submit whilst visiting these third party web sites. We do not accept any responsibility or liability for the privacy practices of such third party web sites and your use of such web sites is at your own risk.

**Dealing with us anonymously**

Where it is lawful and practicable, you can deal with us anonymously or use a pseudonym (e.g. general enquires about the services we can offer you).

How you can help protect your privacy?

You can help us to protect your privacy by:

  * observing our security requirements relating to usernames and passwords; and
  * contacting us when your contact details change.

**How can you contact us?**

If you want further information on how we handle your personal information, if you want to find out about or update the information that we hold about you, or if you want to complain about a possible breach of privacy, please contact us in one of the following ways:

  * By Phone on: +61 3 98663710
  * By Email on: [info@ausregistry.com.au](mailto:info@ausregistry.com.au)
  * Write to us at: PO Box 33125, Melbourne Victoria 3004, Australia

If you are unsatisfied with the resolution of any complaints you make, you can refer the matter to the Privacy Commissioner by calling 1300 363 992.

For more information on privacy please refer to the Privacy Commissioner’s website [www.privacy.gov.au](http://www.privacy.gov.au/).

If your complaint is not satisfactorily resolved, you may apply to the Privacy Commissioner to have the concern heard and determined. For more information about how to lodge a complaint with the Privacy Commissioner, please contact the Commissioner’s hotline service on 1300 363 992 or if calling from outside Australia on +61 2 9284 9749.

**Amendment to policy**

We may discontinue or amend any part or the whole of this policy from time to time at our absolute discretion. We will provide you with notice of any variation or amendment to this policy by publishing the varied policy on this website. You accept that by doing that, we will have provided you with sufficient notice of the variation of this policy and that you will be bound by the varied policy when you next visit this website. Your continued use of the website following such notification will represent an agreement by you to be bound by this policy as amended.
